hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the TSA automation
playlist so today I'm going to talk
about another problem or issue which is
generally faced by many people when they
are working with tosa especially around
date formatting now uh every application
has got its own format of date and many
times uh we need to perform date
calculations and we need to also change
a date to a specific format but uh the
issue which happens is sometimes uh tosa
will not accept the date format which
you are trying to convert to okay uh
because tosa has got its own uh format
where which is either defined by the
system where it is installed or it is
defined within tosa itself okay so
sometimes the conversion even though uh
you can use the dated function to make
the calculations and to make the
conversion to a specific format but the
source format will not be accepted as a
valid format by tosa and then it throws
up an error okay so I have come across
this scenario multiple times and that is
the reason I thought I would share this
particular solution which is a very
simple solution uh which you can apply
all the time whenever you are trying to
convert uh some date format into another
date format but the date format which
you're trying to convert may be of
different format than what tosa accepts
currently okay so uh let's look uh at an
example for this right so this is the
example uh where uh this is the date
which has been provided to us which is
today's date okay uh it is in a specific
format which doesn't match with the
format which I have currently on my
system uh my system has a date format of
uh DD mm and yyy but I have provided uh
date which is yyy MM and DD okay uh and
then we need to convert this particular
date into this format right so this is
uh the scenario this is what we need to
do so uh let's go ahead and create a new
test case folder here and I will call it
dates okay and then I'm going to create
a test case here called
format
date okay so the first thing which uh uh
I can do is uh I can set a buffer here
okay so I'm going to use the tbox set
buffer and I'm going to call it
today
date okay and uh I'm going to define the
date which I have picked so uh which is
in a specific format we know that right
so I'm going to give it a value like
2024 and then 03 and then 07 okay so
this is the value which I have provided
and now uh I'm going to convert this
date into the specified format so I'm
going to call it new date okay so this
is again a set
buffer um and here uh I am going to call
the date function okay so we already
know about the date function um you can
do different types of calculations you
can also uh change it to a specific
format right so inside this we are going
to pick up the buffer of uh today's date
right so the buffer which we have
already created so I'm going to use it
here and then uh we'll leave this empty
okay we are not doing any offset and
after that we are providing a format
here right so that format would be DD
and then mm which will be in capital and
then y y y okay so this is the format
which we want it to
convert um and then I'm going to close
this okay so this is the new date this
is the today's date okay um so
everything looks good now um and we have
used the right date function to convert
it into a specific format right okay so
we would expect this to run so let's go
ahead and run this and let's see whether
tosa can actually convert this date or
not okay so what you'll notice is this
test case will fail okay and even though
we have used the correct function um and
we have used all the correct formats
still uh it is failing and the reason is
the value which we have provided cannot
be interpreted by tosa as a date
according to this particular format okay
so in tosa this is the format which is
currently set okay and it will always
try to interpret this as the right
format okay so from here it can convert
it into a different format using the
date function but if you're trying to
put some other date okay which is in a
different format then tosa cannnot
interpret it as a date okay so we have
to change that interpretation of tosa so
that it considers this as a valid
date okay and how we can do that is by
defining a test configuration parameter
for our test case Okay so uh go into the
particular test
configuration and then from here we will
try to add a test configuration
parameter here uh we have to choose
something called the tosa date format
okay so it is a system defined test
configuration parameter and here uh we
are going to choose any particular value
right there are multiple values which
you can choose from um and you can
choose any particular format from here
okay so uh we want to choose this
particular format because this is the
format uh which we have provided okay so
I can choose this uh if you want any
other format you can also choose that so
once you define this test configuration
parameter now tosa will be forced to uh
consider this format as a correct valid
date format now when we run this it
should be running
successfully okay so now you can see
that it was able to set the buffer with
this state and then it was able to
convert
into the specified format
okay so uh this is how you can basically
change uh the interpretation of tosa so
that it considers a specific format as a
valid date format okay because uh tosa
will have its own date format which it
will always try to interpret as the
correct date so uh even though uh you
know how to convert the dates using the
different date functions this is also
one aspect which you need to consider
when you are working with different date
formats and different applications have
got a different date formats so this uh
this way you can always work with those
different
formats that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video